VIRENDRA ADHIKARI

Current Address

F3-403, Provident Welworth City Yelahanka Doddaballapur Road, Marasandra, Amanikere, Bengaluru – 562157, Karnataka

Contact Number:+91-98184-80809 Contact mail id: adhikari.virendra@live.com Permanent Address:

B-39, Hill View Garden, Alwar Bypass Road, Bhiwadi – 301018 Rajasthan

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To obtain a position that provides me the opportunity to reach my full potential professionally and personally utilizing my Language abilities and experience gained during 13+ years of experience as well as to enhance my knowledge about new and emerging trends in the IT Sector.

PERSONAL DETAIL

Gender	Male		
Date of Birth	30 th December 1983		
Father's Name	Shri Chander Mani	Retired Serviceman	
Mother's Name	Smt Tulsi Devi	House-wife	
Brother Name	Laxman Adhikari	In-service (Japan)	
Sister Name	Asha Koirala	Housewife	
Spouse Name	Pooja Adhikari	Housewife	
Daughter's Name	Vidhi Adhikari	Daughter	
	Ridhima Adhikari	Daughter	
Hobbies	Playing soccer,cricket, hockey		
Language Known	Hindi, English, Japanese, Nepalese		
Passport Number	Z3380381 (valid till Sep'25)		
Current CTC	20 lakh Per annum		

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

- Senior Secondary (XII) from CBSE Board (Year 2001)
- > Bachelors in Commerce (Pass) from University of Delhi (Year 2007)

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Japanese language	JLPT LEVEL 4	Passed in year 2005
	JLPT LEVEL 3	Passed in year 2008
	JLPT N3	Passed in year 2010
	JLPT N2	Passed in year 2022
Computer Skills	Operating System	Windows, Redhat Linux / Ubuntu
	Application	Microsoft Office / Office 365
	Programming	Python / JavaScript / HTML / CSS

COURSES / CERTIFICATIONS

'O' LEVEL CERTIFICATION	DOEACC SOCIETY (ACCRIDATED BY AICTE)
Crash Course on Python Programming`	COURSERA

PURSUING SKILL

EXPERIENCE

Organization	Period	Experience (in years)	Roles & Duties
Sakura Tours Pvt Ltd	2006~08	2	Tour Executive (Tour Costing, Accommodation Arrangements, Travel Arrangements including land & Air, Escort Services)
Honda Express Logistics India Private Limited	2008-09	0.6	Live interpretation Japanese to English and Vice-versa. Technical translation of mails, specifications, procedures from Japanese to English and vice versa. Administrative service handling for Japanese Expats in India including Accommodation, Visa Services, Travel Arrangements, Health Support Services
Maruti Suzuki India Limited	2010~13	3.3	 Assistant Manager (Japanese Administration Department – JPAD) Live Technical Interpretation (Internal / Overseas meetings, Supplier meetings, Government Technical translation of mails, specifications, procedures from Japanese to English and vice versa Administrative service handling for Japanese Expats in India including Accommodation, Visa Services, Travel Arrangements, Health Support Services coordinator for Overseas Training (@ Japan) for Indian Employees Administrative service handling for Japanese Expats in India including Accommodation, Visa Services, Travel Arrangements, Health Support Services
Honda Cars India Limited	2013~16	3.2	 Senior Executive (Quality & Delivery Department) Live Technical Interpretation (Internal / Overseas meetings, Supplier meetings, Supplier Quality Audits etc) Technical translation of mails, specifications, procedures from Japanese to English and vice versa Administrative service handling for Japanese Expats in India including Accommodation, Visa Services, Travel Arrangements, Health Support Services Administrator for GSR(Global Sourcing Request), web based portal used for import / export of Automotive parts worldwide in Honda Group. Being part of GSR (Global Sourcing Request) Management System (web-based sourcing request portal) handled and managed global request for part sourcing including import/export of parts across the HONDA Locations.
Hitachi Zosen India Private Limited	2016~19	3.3	Assistant Manager – Administration Department Japanese Language Coordinator between Japan & India HO. Administrative service handling for Japanese Expats in India including Accommodation, Visa Services, Travel Arrangements, Health Support Services Coordinator / Support member for Statutory Audits, Internal Audits & IT related activities of Company. Assisting Business Clients from Japan in India and facilitating with Probable India Customers.
Musashi Auto Parts Limited	2019~till date	2+	 Senior Interpreter / Translator Live Technical Interpretation (Internal / Overseas meetings, Supplier meetings, Government agencies) Technical translation of mails, specifications, procedures from Japanese to English and vice versa Administrative service handling for Japanese Expats in India including Accommodation, Visa Services, Travel Arrangements, Health Support Services Being part of SAP implementation during Oct.,2020 to Mar.,21 and have acted as an interface between Japanese expat and SAP consultant on various topics such as production punching stations, work center defining,

grouping of work center into a cost center, maintenance related, overall operational processes such as defining plant, profit center, business places etc.
Currently I am a part of Production OEE (Overall Equipment Efficiency) Monitoring system which is under implementation, and acting as an interface between Japanese expats and consultant on various topics which includes rendering of web pages, Handling of Database (MongoDB), how to use ERP module (BIZNEXT, specific to vendor) to render required data on web pages, generating the reports and data in desired formats, managing the users with access and authentication etc.

Date: 22nd August 2022

(Virendra Adhikari)